Software Engineer

Trained in machine learning, my passion lies in software engineering. My ideal job combines software development with implementing of machine learning algorithms and Al. Years as a graduate student researcher gave me the tools to work independently while a previous engineering career in the field of medical device manufacturing gave me the experience of working on large-scale projects with cross-fucntional teams.

Technical Tools

Languages: C · C++ · Python · Java · Objective-C · Bash · R · Matlab · SQL · Lisp · LETEX · XML · JSON · YAML **Productivity:** Emacs · Vim · R Studio · Android Studio · Xcode · Eclipse · Git · Gerrit · Jira · Confluence · Slack

Platforms: Linux · Docker · Tomcat · SQL Server · Oracle · JDBC · OpenGL **Graphing:** Gnuplot · Graphviz · Xfig · AutoCAD · Bokeh · ggplot2 · wxWidgets

Experience in Industry

Trusted Autonomy, a Beyond Limits company

Leader in industrial-grade Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) software

AI Software Engineer

- Develop artificial intelligence software
- · Implement machine learning algorithms

InAuth, Inc., an American Express company

Leader in mobile-first authentication and fraud prevention for mobile applications and browsers

SDET

July 2016 - October 2017

October 2017 - present

• Developed cross-platform, test automation framework for the company's mobile SDK products. It runs on Linux and OS X, operates on Android and iOS devices, is extensible and provides end-to-end automation, writing results to an MS Excel spreadsheet in the cloud. It reduces a month of work of three QA testers to two hours.

Children's Hospital Los Angeles

Award-winning, non-profit, research hospital providing life-saving care to children

Data Scientist

December 2014 - July 2016

- Developed algorithm to diagnose patients. It transformed each patient's heterogeneous, messy and irregularly sampled longitudinal data from electronic health records into a fixed-length feature vector, relative to every other patient in the ICU. The interrelation between variables and their timing information was modeled in a principled way as a marked point process. The number of clusters was automatically selected by the algorithm.
- Implemented packages in R and Python for data cleaning and analysis

Google, Inc.

Multinational, technology company specializing in Internet-related services and products

Software Engineering Intern

June 2013 - September 2013

- Contributed to open source software, Flexible I/O Tester (fio)
- Developed Linux utility in C to test data integrity and retention of storage devices

Experience in Academia

University of California Riverside

Public research university part of the University of California system

Graduate Student Researcher

June 2012 - September 2014

• Implemented clustering algorithms (20K lines of C++ code) in support of my research

Associate Instructor

April 2012 - June 2012

• Taught CS 14 Introduction to Data Structures and Algorithms

Teaching Assistant

September 2009 - June 2013

Held laboratory sessions, graded assignments, and held office hours for various CS courses

Harvey Mudd College

Top-ranked college of science, engineering and mathematics

Instructor

January 2011 - May 2011

Taught CS 151 Artificial Intelligence

Juan Casse page 2 of 2

Previous Professional Experience

Lifescan, a Johnson & Johnson company

Manufacturer of blood glucose monitoring systems for home and hospital use

Staff Engineer

January 2002 - December 2004

- Introduced new technology automation to our manufacturing process
- Worked closely with machine builders through conceptual design, reviews and validation

Senior Manufacturing Engineer

August 1997 - January 2002

- Improved process yield from 75% to 85% through 6-sigma projects
- Integrated vision inspection systems on all manufacturing lines to ensure correct labeling

Baxter Biotech Group Fenwal Division

Medical device manufacturer of products used in the delivery of fluids/drugs and hemodialysis

Project Engineer - Factory Automation

September 1993 - September 1997

- · Designed and built automated manufacturing equipment for the company's facilities worldwide
- Supervised personnel and coordinated work in automation group's machine shop
- Integrated radiation-based sterilization process

Other Technical Experience

Web IDE (2018) Web-based IDE for Al cognitive engine, deployed in Docker. Python, Flask, Javascript, CSS, HTML

Experimenter (2015) Multi-threaded, GUI-based workflow tool. C++, wxWidgets

Automatic Grader (2012) Coding assignment grading and reporting system. Bash, C++

Interactive 3D Visualization (2011) GUI for viewing a clustering of cubed data. C++, OpenGL

Convoy Routing (2007) Genetic algorithm for optimal scheduling of convoys on shared roads. C++, Java

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) University of California, Riverside

December 2014

• Dissertation: Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data

M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) California State University, Long Beach

May 2008

Thesis: Convoy Routing and scheduling using Augmented Beam Search, RSBS

B.S. in Electrical Engineering (GPA 2.5) Marquette University, Milwaukee

August 1992

• Senior Project: Robotic arm to demonstrate cell manufacturing to future classes

Publications

Islam, Kazi T., Shelton, Christian R., Casse, Juan I. and Wetzel, Randall (2017). Marked Point Process for Severity of Illness Assessment. Proceedings of Machine Learning for Healthcare 2017. JMLR W&C Track Volume 68.

Casse, Juan Ignacio (2014). **Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data**. Ph.D. Dissertation, University of California Riverside, Riverside, CA.

Casse, J., Shelton, C., Hanneman, R. (2013). A new criterion function for exploratory blockmodeling for structural and regular equivalence. Social Networks, 35(1), 32–50.

Casse, J.I., Shelton, C.R., and Hanneman R.A. (2011). Alternating Optimization Algorithm for Block-modeling Two-way Two-mode Data with Unknown Number of Clusters. Regular Session on Social Networks for the 2011 ASA.

Goldstein, D., Shehab, T., Casse, J., and Lin, H. (2010). **On the formulation and solution of the convoy routing problem**. Transportation Research Part E: Logistics and Transportation Review, 46(4), 520.

Casse, J.I. (2008). Convoy Routing and Scheduling using Augmented Beam Search RSBS. Master's thesis, California State University, Long Beach, CA.